TENZIN: Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Water.
When I was a boy,
my father, Avatar Aang,
told me the story
of how he and his friends
heroically ended the Hundred Year War.
Avatar Aang and Fire Lord Zuko
transformed the Fire Nation colonies
into the United Republic of Nations,
a society where benders
and non-benders
from all over the world could live and
thrive together in peace and harmony.
They named the capital of this
great land Republic City.
Avatar Aang accomplished
many remarkable things in his life.
But sadly, his time in this world
came to an end.
And like the cycle of the seasons,
the cycle of the Avatar began anew.
(WIND HOWLING)
The White Lotus has
honored my family by coming.
Thank you.
Welcome.
We have investigated many claims,
both here and in the Northern Tribe.
All have turned out to be false.
Then you should be happy to know
your search has come to an end.
What makes you so sure
your daughter is the one?
Korra, please come in here.
(CRASH)
I'm the Avatar. You got to deal with it.
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
She's strong.
She lacks restraint.
(YELLS IN SURPRISE)
(GROANS)
Wahoo!
(LAUGHING) Hey, why all the
doom and gloom, people?
We should be celebrating!
Three elements down, one to go.
You're getting ahead of yourself
as usual, Korra.
We haven't decided if you passed
your fire bending test yet.
Ever since you were a little girl,
you've excelled
at the physical side of bending,
but completely ignored the spiritual side.
The Avatar must master both.
I haven't ignored it,
it just doesn't come as easy to me.
But that's why I should start training
with Tenzin immediately.
He's Mr. Spiritual.
Do you believe she's ready,
Master Katara?
Yes, if anyone can teach her what she
needs to learn, it's Tenzin.
Very well, Korra.
It's time for you to begin
your airbending training.
Yes! Finally!
I mean, thank you all for believing in me.
(CHUCKLES)
Naga, you should've seen it.
I kicked some Firebender butt.
And I passed.
Tenzin will be here in a few days.
(LAUGHS)
Just taking Naga out for a stroll.
Don't worry, we're not going far.
Naga, go! Thaﬂa girl!
Go, go, go!
IKKI: Are we there yet? Are we there yet?
Are we there yet?
It looks like we're there.
I know this. This is very familiar.
Are we here yet?
- Ooh, please tell me we're here!
- Yes, lkki.
As I've been telling you
for the last 15 minutes,
we are finally here.
IKKII Wee!
(assume)
Hello, Mother.
I can't tell you how happy I am
to see you.
Please... Help me.
(LAUGHING) Unhand me,
strange woman!
That's your grandmother, Meelo.
It's so good to see all of you.
Gran-Gran, I've been reading
all about your old adventures,
I've been dying to ask you.
What happened to Zuko's mom?
Well, Jinora, it's an incredible tale...
Gran-Gran, you look old.
How old are you?
And why is it so cold in the South Pole?
Can we make a campfire
and all huddle around it,
and tell scary stories
and make snowmen?
And then can you make the snowmen
move with waterbending and chase us?
Wouldn't that be fun? Huh? Wouldn't it?
Pema, let me help you.
Careful, now. Careful.
Stop doting on me.
I'm not helpless' I'm just pregnant.
The baby's strong.
I see another Airbender in your future.
All I want is one child like me.
A nice non-bender, who doesn't blast
wind in my face every five seconds.
Mommy, look! I'm a Snowbender!
Were Tenzin and his siblings this crazy
when they were kids?
Kya and Bumi certainly were,
but Tenzin has always
been rather serious.
Mother, please.
Korra?
Look at you. So big and strong.
You've grown into quite
the young Avatar.
Master Tenzin, I'm so glad you're here.
I can't wait to get started.
Yes, well... (SIGHS)
You're going to have to tell her
sooner or later.
Wait, tell me what?
You're not staying, are you?
I'm afraid not.
We're only visiting for the night.
Then I have to return to Republic City.
But, no' you're supposed to move here.
You're supposed to teach me.
TENZIN: I'm sorry, Korra.
Your airbending training
is going to have to wait.
KORRA: So how long until you're
ready to teach me airbending?
A week? A month?
It could be much longer.
I don't understand.
Why are you making me wait?
I have a responsibility to Republic City.
I'm one of its leaders.
And the situation there
is very unstable right now.
But you also have a responsibility
to teach me.
Believe me, I'd be happy
to find another airbending master,
but you're the only one.
We're stuck with each other.
I wish there were another way.
Wait, there is!
If you can't stay here,
then I'll go back to Republic City
with you.
It's perfect!
(SCOFFS) Absolutely not!
The city is far too dangerous.
Avatar Aang tasked us
with keeping you safe
while you mastered the four elements.
I get that, but I don't think keeping me
locked up in this compound
like a prisoner is what he had in mind.
I know this is difficult to accept
but it's not the right time
for you to come to the city.
Whatever.
(BOTH SIGH)
Goodbye, Gran-Gran.
Oogi, yip yip.
(NAGA WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTING)
KATARA: Nice night
for an escape, isn't it?
I have to leave.
I have to find my own path as the Avatar.
I know you do.
Aang's time has passed.
My brother and many of my friends
are gone.
It's time for you and your generation
to take on the responsibility
of keeping peace and balance
in the world.
And I think you're going to be
a great Avatar.
Thank you.
Goodbye, Korra.
(NAGA GRUNTING)
KORRA: Mom, Dad...
I'll miss you.
We love you so much.
(SHIP CREAKING)
Naga, we're here!
-(MAN GRUNTING}
- Thanks for the ride!
KORRA: Wow, look at this place.
I've never seen so many Sato-mobiles.
Air Temple Island.
That's where Tenzin lives.
You ready for a little swim, girl?
(SNIFFING)
Okay, okay!
Food first, then Air Temple.
- Watch it, Naga! Look out!
-(SATO-MOBILES SCREECHING)
MAN: Watch where you're going!
Whoops! Sorry about that. Excuse us.
Coming through. Heads up.
Sorry, we're new in town.
(SNIFFING VIGOROUSLY)
Naga, wait.
(NAGA WHIMPERS)
We'll take one of everything, please.
That'll be 20 yuans.
Uh... I don't have any money.
Then what good are you to me?
Don't worry, girl. This city's huge.
I bet we can find a place to rustle up
something to eat.
(GASPS)
Uh, say, think I can get one of them
tasty-smelling fishies?
Oh! Uh...
Yeah, sure!
So do you live in that bush?
Yes, presently that is
what I do call home.
Took me a while to procure a bush
that beauteous.
This park is quite popular
with all the vagabonds.
So there are a lot of you out here?
I thought everyone in this city
was living it up.
(VAGABOND LAUGHS)
You got a lot to learn, newcomer.
Welcome to Republic City!
-(WHISTLE BLOWS)
- Hey, you! Stop! You can't fish here!
You best skedaddle! Whoop!
(WHISTLES)
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
(PANTING)
Are you tired of living under the
tyranny of benders?
Then join the Equalistsl
For too long,
the bending elite of this city
have forced non-benders
to live as lower-class citizens.
Join Amon, and together we will tear
down the bending establishment!
KORRA: What are you talking about?
Bending is the coolest thing in the world.
Oh, yeah?
Let me guess, you're a bender.
Yeah, lam.
And I bet you'd just love to
knock me off this platform
with some waterbending, huh?
I'm seriously thinking about it.
This is what's wrong with the city.
Benders like this girl
only use their power to oppress us!
(JEERING AND AGREEING)
What?
I'm not oppressing anyone.
You're... You're oppressing yourself.
That didn't even make sense.
Excuse me, I think I'm lost.
How do I get to Air Temple Island
from here?
Just head down this street...
You should get moving, young lady.
It isn't safe.
Mr. Chung, please tell me
that you have my money,
or else I can't guarantee
I can protect your fine establishment.
I'm sorry.
Business has been slow. Please.
Take one of my phonographs.
(MR. CHUNG YELLING IN FEAR)
My friend here is not a music lover.
Give me the money, or else...
KORRA: Or else what, hoodlum'?
(LAUGHING)
Since you're obviously fresh off the boat,
let me explain a couple things.
You're in Triple Threat Triad territory,
and we're about to put you
in the hospital.
KORRA: You're the only ones
who are going to need a hospital.
And for your sake,
I hope there's one nearby.
Who do you think you are?
Why don't you come and find out?
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(YELLING)
- What just happened?
- Did she just earthbend?
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(SHRIEKS)
- Can she firebend, too'?
- Could she be...
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(CHUCKLING) Got an idea about
who I am now, chumps?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Come on!
KORRA: You're not getting away.
(HUBCAP ROLLING)
(ALL GROAN)
-(SIREN WAILING)
-(HOWLING)
POLICEMAN: (OVER MEGAPHONE)
Police! Freeze where you are!
KORRA: Cool. Metalbenders.
I caught the bad guys for you, Officers.
Arrest them.
(GRUNTING)
You're under arrest, too.
(GASPS)
What do you mean I'm under arrest?
Those are the bad guys over there.
They were smashing up a shop.
POLICEMAN: From the looks of it, you
smashed up a lot more than that.
Wait, you can't arrest me.
Let me explain.
You can explain yourself all you like
down at headquarters.
(POLICEMAN GRUNTING)
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
Ugh!
(YELLING)
-(TIRES SCREECHING)
- MAN: Hey!
(SIRENS WAILING)
(NAGA GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(NAGA WHIMPERS)
POLICE OFFICER: Let's see.
Multiple counts of destruction of private
and city property.
Not to mention evading arrest.
You're in a whole mess of trouble,
young lady.
But there were some thugs
threatening a helpless shopkeeper
-and I had to...
- Can it!
You should have called the police
and stayed out of the way.
But I couldn't just sit by and do nothing.
It's my duty to help people.
See, I'm the Avatar.
Oh, I am well aware of who you are.
And your "Avatar" title might impress
some people, but not me.
All right. Fine.
Then I want to talk to
whoever's in charge.
You're talking to her. I'm Chief Beifong.
Wait. Beifong?
Lin Beifong? You're Toph's daughter!
What of it?
Well, then why are you treating me
like a criminal?
Avatar Aang and your mother
were friends.
They saved the world together.
That's ancient history.
And it's got diddly-squat to do
with the mess you're in right now.
You can't just waltz in here
and dole out vigilante justice
like you own the place.
Chief. Councilman Tenzin is here.
(SIGHS) Let him in.
KORRA: Tenzin.
Sorry, I got a little sidetracked
on my way to see you.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Lin, you are looking radiant as usual.
Cut the garbage, Tenzin.
Why is the Avatar in Republic City?
I thought you were supposed to be
moving down to the South Pole
to train her.
My relocation has been delayed.
The Avatar, on the other hand,
will be heading back
to the South Pole immediately.
- Where she will stay put.
- But...
If you would be so kind
as to drop the charges against Korra,
I will take full responsibility
for today's regrettable events
and cover all the damages.
(SIGHS) Fine. Get her out of my city.
Always a pleasure, Lin. Let's go, Korra.
Hmm.
KORRA: Tenzin, please.
Don't send me back home.
You blatantly disobeyed my wishes,
and the Orders of the White Lotus.
Katara agreed with me
that I should come.
She said my destiny is in Republic City.
Don't bring my mother into this!
Look, I can't wait any longer
to finish my training.
Being cooped up and hidden away
from the world
isn't helping me become a better Avatar.
I saw a lot of the city today
and ifs totally out of whack.
I understand now why you need to stay.
Republic City does need you.
But it needs me, too!
(STRUGGLING FOR WORDS)
Is this your polar bear-dog, miss?
(PANTING)
(SIGHS)
- Korra!
Are you coming to live with us
on the Island?
No, I'm sorry, lkki.
- I have to go home now.
- IKKI: Avvw!
TENZIN: Wait.
I have done my best
to guide Republic City
towards the dream my father had for it.
But you are right, it has fallen
out of balance since he passed.
I thought I should put off your training
in order to uphold his legacy.
But you are his legacy.
You may stay and train
airbending here with me.
Republic City needs its Avatar
once again.
Yes! Thank you! You're the best!
KIDS: Yay!
(IKKI GIGGLING)
(SIGHS)
(CROWD CHEERING AND WHISTLING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hello? I'm Korra, your new Avatar.
Does this mean you've moved
to Republic City'?
Were you trying to send a message
to the Triads yesterday?
Will you be fighting crime or
the anti-bending revolution? Or both?
Will you be working with Chief Beifong
and the police?
Uh... Yes, I am definitely here to stay,
but, honestly...
I don't exactly have a plan yet.
See, I'm still in training, but...
Look, all I know is Avatar Aang
meant for this city
to be the center of peace
and balance in the world.
And I believe we can make
his dream a reality.
I look forward to serving you
(OVER RADIO) Fm so happy to be here
Thank you, Republic City.
MAN: AH right, that's
ab' the questions the..
Amon' how do you want to handle this?
AMON: So the Avatar has arrived early.
It looks like we will have to accelerate
our plans.